<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Introduction</title>
    <link>https://huckleberryinsights.github.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Introduction</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://huckleberryinsights.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Knitting to Output with Rmarkdown</title>
      <link>https://huckleberryinsights.github.io/blog/2017-04-13-publishing-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huckleberryinsights.github.io/blog/2017-04-13-publishing-documents/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial’s purposeManipulating data and building visuals is the bread and butter of the R language - but what can get lost in the fold is the ability to easily and quickly push analysis out for folks to see. Using knitr and rmarkdown makes that significantly easier, and exists at the press of a button. In this tutorial, we’re going to press those buttons.
What are the packages?There are a ton of ways to get information from R out into the world - ranging from static Word or PDF documents all the way to interactive web applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://huckleberryinsights.github.io/blog/2017-04-11-into-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huckleberryinsights.github.io/blog/2017-04-11-into-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Today’s purposeTo walk through the tidyverse and become familiar with the functions that it provides the user and how it can make your life so much better to use.
What the heck even is a tidyverse?tidyverse is a collection of R packages providing an all-inclusive resource for data science (well, almost). When you library(tidyverse) the following packages are loaded up as dependencies:
PackageDescriptionggplot2Graphics-building package based on The Grammar of Graphics mapping aesthetics to data visuallytibbleWrapper on traditional dataframes allowing for better printing and viewing datatidyrPackage to easily and quickly get your data into a rectangular format (if not already in one)readrSuper fast package for reading in rectangular data (like csv, tsv, and fwf)purrrA set of tools for working with functions and vectors for functional programming techniquesdplyrQuickly and efficiently manipulate data with a Grammar of Manipulation (just made that up)Within each of these there are a handful of other dependencies - not all of which I am going to talk through.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>